♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we pass by the magnificent scenery ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Could it be that both of us
are filled with desolation? ♪
♪ As flowers bloom and wither ♪
♪ May we lead such a life ♪
♪ Contemplate the vastness
of Heaven and Earth ♪
♪ Turning back, you and I ♪
♪ Seize the current moment ♪
♪ The sky is painted
with a gentle pallet of pastel colors ♪
♪ Let's walk together ♪
♪ Even if ♪
♪ The snow in front of us ♪
♪ Will dye our hair white ♪
♪ In an instant ♪
[Joy of Life Season 2]
[Adapted from Mao Ni's Joy of Life
on Yuewen Group's Qidian platform]
[Episode 5]
Shut the business down
for the time being.
You calm the ladies down.
Once I return to the Capital properly,
I will help them.
All right.
By the way,
there is this lady
with the surname Jin here.
Look after her well.
Return the indenture to her.
Is this fair to Wan'er?
The business is doing quite well.
Do you really want to close it down?
I dare not continue.
Aren't you intrepid?
I wouldn't cross the boundary.
Well.
I should get going.
You should rejoin the diplomatic corps
as soon as possible.
Don't delay their return to the Capital.
I will.
Your Highness,
please send someone
to take care of the Tengs.
Don't worry.
How are you going
to deal with Chengze...
I will get to the bottom of it.
Good, then.
We will expect news
from Shijia Town in the next few days.
Well, enough said.
Once you return to the Capital,
let's achieve big things.
Goodbye, Your Highness.
Xian, you must listen to me.
The Crown Prince and the Second Prince
are locking horns.
Let's not meddle in it.
Your head could be lopped off.
It's not your head, though.
None of us should die, anyway.
It was a big mess in the Capital
upon receiving the news
of your death last time.
It was an uproar. Many people came
to our residence bearing gifts.
Don't make us experience that again.
When I come back here,
return all those things.
They won't take them.
Why not?
Mr. Fan, think about this.
If you are not dead,
no one dares to take back the gifts.
If you are alive,
those street smarts
will probably send more gifts.
You are never fit to be a bureaucrat.
This is nonsense.
Not at all.
This is the bureaucracy
and customary diplomacy.
Well, shut down the business.
Everything is taken care of now.
We are leaving.
Xian, don't go yet.
What do you mean, "everything"?
What about this one?
What should we do with him?
You will take care of him.
Me?
You knocked him out with a hand strike.
What else could I do?
Let him witness
how his two brothers fight?
You are quite considerate.
You are my brother. You should help me.
What about me?
From now on, lock yourself up at home.
Don't leave home before I come back.
All right.
Don't tell anyone
about what happened today.
I know.
Don't worry.
Everything will be all right.
Wait for me.
I will wait for you.
Take care, Young Master.
Making a living isn't easy.
I was supposed to be on this table.
Sizhe.
Why are you asleep?
Perhaps I'm still growing,
and I get sleepy easily.
It shouldn't be.
I remember that someone was in this room
who came out of nowhere
and knocked me out.
Then, I was lying here.
Impossible.
You said someone from that corner
hand-stroked you,
and you laid on the table.
Seems like it.
Impossible.
You seemed strange
when you came in here.
You went straight to the bed.
You said you were tired
and wanted to take a nap.
I think you had a dream.
A dream?
Sizhe, what happened to your eye?
A donkey kicked me.
A donkey? You have a donkey?
No. I dreamed of it.
A donkey kicked me in my dream.
You had an interesting dream.
I know.
I also dreamed
of two dogs fighting here.
Well, let's continue with the songs.
Chengping, listen.
We are not listening to songs today.
You should return to the palace
and take a good rest.
Why?
Recently, our mental state
has been in poor condition.
Right?
We have a lot of dreams.
I was kicked by a donkey in my dream.
And you were
knocked out by Fan Xian, right?
Fan Xian?
I mean, a bad guy knocked you out
in your dream.
Right?
So, let's call it a day.
Mr. Fan,
they are not here.
Where...
Where did they go?
If the Second Prince didn't seize them,
where could they go?
Did you offend anyone here?
While I was away
for the past six months,
there might be some monetary conflicts.
But it wouldn't get the family involved.
Mr. Fan, you have to return
to the diplomatic corps by yourself.
I'm sorry. I can't accompany you.
I need to go searching for them.
I will go with you.
Mr. Fan, you have to leave
before it's too late.
Don't worry. They are more important.
Dear.
You were inside?
Where is Baba?
Why did you avoid me?
I'm wiping your sweat.
Why nervous?
We were inside the room.
I was putting her to sleep.
But I didn't see you.
Then,
why did you disappear?
Someone took us away.
What do you mean?
We were protected.
Protect?
Who?
Who else could it be?
Chen Pingping?
Exactly.
Mr. Chen wants me
to relay a message to you.
The Tengs have been released.
He will escort them
to Danzhou to settle down.
He asks you
if you would want to meet them
before they depart.
No.
The farther I stay from them,
the safer they can be.
Mr. Chen advises you to return
to the diplomatic corps quickly.
What actually does he want?
Mr. Chen says
that you might be wary of him
after the trip to Northern Qi.
But he won't explain himself
because words are meaningless sometimes.
How he treats you
depends not on his words
but on his actions.
Can you see through him?
I doubt anyone in this world can.
Dear,
thank you for looking after Baba.
Mr. Fan and I should rejoin
the diplomatic corps now.
Mr. Fan, where are you?
We are reaching the Capital soon.
Hurry back, or I will be exposed.
Did you see that?
This fellow
talks to Fan Xian's ashes every day.
I can't hear what he's talking about.
But I'm truly impressed
by his loyalty.
Where are you now?
I'm going crazy.
Well,
the corps is reaching the Capital.
Fan Xian's death
is confirmed.
Let's go
and report to His Highness.
He hasn't been out for days?
Yes, we delivered the meals to his room.
Is he sick?
He eats a lot.
We also prepared yogurt for him.
With fruits.
He doesn't look unwell.
Is anyone else in the room?
No.
You won't know.
Boys at this age
could do anything.
Give that to me. You may go.
Yes.
Mother, do you want to come in?
I brought you yogurt.
You can check under the bed.
There is a cabinet over there.
No one here, right?
Then, why do you coop yourself up?
You aren't usually like this.
He won't let me go out.
Who?
No one. I don't want to go out.
Why not?
Are you in trouble?
Stop asking.
I can't go out. That's all.
Do you have a run-in with a girl?
What girl? There is no such girl.
No. Stop guessing.
How long are you going
to stay in your room?
I don't know either.
Perhaps I still have to wait
for a while more.
Are you waiting for someone?
No... No one. Please stop asking.
Enough.
A girl?
I wish it were a girl.
It's a man.
Mother,
did Father
ask about me?
Why would he ask?
I haven't greeted him these days.
Isn't he angry?
No.
He has been in a good mood
since you didn't show up.
I bet he is.
Father has never
had expectations for me.
Oh, my.
I was just kidding.
It's fine. You don't have to comfort me.
Since childhood,
I have always known
that Father is never satisfied
with everything I do.
No matter how well I do,
he thinks I'm useless.
Mother,
if I could never
do one thing in this life
that makes Father proud,
wouldn't my life be a failure?
Sizhe,
he is your father.
It's not that he looks down on you.
He just expects nothing less from you.
So, can you tell me who that guy is?
Mr. Fan, do you feel better?
It's not serious.
Why can it not be serious?
Since the battle
where Xiao En was captured,
the Dominant Qi in your body
has been out of control.
Fortunately, I found this carriage
so you can rest well.
If not, you would be
coughing up blood again.
The confirmed death of Fan Xian
has relieved His Highness
of his biggest concern.
After returning to the Capital,
I will commend you all.
It's a shame that he is reduced to ashes.
If not, we could reassure His Highness
by showing Fan Xian's body.
That's enough.
How much longer
until we reunite with the corps?
We should be able to catch up with them
before dark.
I need some fresh air.
Just stay inside.
Fan Xian?
What a surprise.
It truly is a surprise.
Xie Bi'an, I have already died for days.
You still follow the diplomatic corps.
Are you keeping vigil for me?
Kill him.
Let him die one more time.
Wang, charge!
Mr. Fan, it's a cliff.
Take a chance!
Mr. Fan,
we won.
Thanks for accompanying me all along.
We need to part now.
Go back.
Tell Li Chengze
to wait for me at the Capital.
Mr. Xie, aren't we chasing after them?
It's already close to the Capital.
We can't attack the diplomatic corps.
At this point,
he has come back to life.
Mr. Fan, you are back!
I'm back too.
You are all back. That's great!
What a journey.
Finally, I made it back alive.
Mr. Yan said you wouldn't make it.
What nonsense is he talking about?
Let me smash this first.
Don't.
Whose convoy is that behind?
The Crown Princess of Northern Qi.
The Crown Princess of Northern Qi?
Where did she come from?
They have been following
the diplomatic corps.
Her convoy caught up
right after you guys left.
The young Northern Qi emperor
appointed a marriage alliance
with the Qing State.
They have been urging us to travel fast.
Thanks to Mr. Yan,
we have been able to travel slowly.
Who is she marrying?
First Prince.
First Prince?
Isn't he always fighting in the battles?
How can he get married?
[Second Prince's Residence]
Chengru is returning to the Capital?
A new commander took over
his duty at the border.
The First Prince only brought
his personal guards back.
Why is he suddenly transferred back
after so many years?
It's said that he is getting married.
The Crown Princess of Northern Qi
is going to marry the First Prince.
Is he going to take the plunge?
After all, he marries a princess.
When will Chengru arrive in the Capital?
In two days.
They are preparing
to welcome him outside the city.
That's good.
But he might run into Fan Xian there.
How so?
I calculated the timing.
The diplomatic corps Fan Xian being in
and the First Prince
should arrive on the same day.
What a coincidence.
By right, they should enter
through two different city gates.
But if they enter through the same gate,
who do you think will make way?
Pass my order.
Be it a coincidence or a roadwork,
make sure they
use the same city gate.
[Miss Shen, sister of Shen Zhong
of Northern Qi]
Fan Xian?
You guys get along quite well.
You can't be serious.
Can't you see who is being chained?
I did.
What is this supposed to mean?
She isn't from the Qing State.
How could I not be cautious?
Why don't you just kill her
instead of guarding her every day?
Killing her
won't do me any good.
Nor harm.
Stop deluding yourself.
Why did you come back here?
What a question.
My fake death is over.
It's time to come back to life.
You won't.
[Qing]
Mr. Gao.
Wang.
I'm here.
Take this.
What is this for?
Just take it.
Do you have something to ask of me?
We are buddies.
You don't have to do this.
Are these Northern Qi's silver taels?
How did you know?
They smell different.
Gao,
why are you giving me money?
To compensate you.
To compensate me?
What for?
Did you break my things?
No.
I'm paying for your clothes.
You left in haste last time
and had left some clothes here.
Did you lose them?
But they wouldn't cost
this much.
How would the clothes get lost
under my watch?
If it's not,
then why are you paying me?
Someone bought them.
Someone bought them?
Do those old clothes
sell for this much money?
You weren't there.
Every time the diplomatic corps
passed a town,
the place was swarmed with people.
Swarmed?
Did they gather to collect old clothes?
Enough about old clothes.
They came to mourn for Mr. Fan.
Mr. Fan!
Everyone rushed to the carriage
as they thought the diplomatic corps
was the last place Mr. Fan had been.
They were begging in tears,
saying that they wanted
Mr. Fan's clothes
as memorabilia.
The news of his death
really spread so far.
I thought
it would only spread in the Capital.
Not only in the Capital,
but the entire Qing State also knows
you are dead.
This doesn't make sense.
Of course.
It's the publicity campaign
of the Imperial Inspectorate.
What is a publicity campaign?
Someone behind is doing propaganda.
The Imperial Inspectorate alone
isn't able to achieve this.
It's His Majesty.
But His Majesty knows that I'm alive.
Why would he disseminate
news of my death?
His Majesty always considers
the greater good.
So, the motive behind
disseminating news of my death
is for the sake of the Qing State?
It's all for the sake of the Qing State.
If my death benefits the Qing State,
why don't you make it a real one?
What do you want?
I must stay alive
and return to the Capital.
I need to investigate
Li Chengze's thoroughly.
It's not that I want to kill you,
but you simply must die.
I understand.
Unless my fake death has a reasonable
and valid reason,
I will be considered
deceiving the emperor.
It would be best if I could also verify
the literary succession.
How could it be possible?
Is the Crown Princess of Northern Qi
also in the diplomatic corps?
What are you planning?
What is she like?
Just a princess.
It's already late.
Mr. Yan, why do you...
Fan... Fan...
Fan... Fan Xian.
Aren't you already dead?
Have you seen me before?
Secretly.
I'm more surprised than you are.
What do you mean, "secretly"?
During Mother's birthday banquet.
In the back hall.
I saw
you and the Holy Maiden of Northern Qi,
Miss Duoduo,
looking at each other affectionately
in front of everyone.
No! Not affectionate!
Are you that nervous?
Pick it up.
Emissary Fan, are you
not dead enough?
It isn't a real death.
Not a real death.
All right.
Back to your position.
[Crown Princess of Northern Qi]
When I first heard of your death,
I was shocked.
Now
that I see you are safe,
I feel rather relieved.
Fortunately, we didn't
lose a great talent.
Do you not go out much, Your Highness?
I'm a princess.
How could I leave the palace casually?
Got it. That's why you are nervous.
As the Qi royal,
we must be composed
whenever we are.
We won't be nervous.
All right, got it.
Your Highness,
let's talk about something serious.
Before you departed,
what did the Emperor
and the Empress Dowager
inform you?
You may leave.
Mother and His Majesty told me
that you and the Qi State
had a secret smuggling deal.
If you have any news in the future,
you can inform me,
and I will pass it on to Qi.
So, we are on the same side.
Maybe.
That's why I can't die.
You are not dead.
But I can't stay alive either.
If I can't stay alive,
how can we continue our deal?
If so,
how can you keep yourself alive?
Do you lie, Your Highness?
The Qi royal
values integrity.
We never commit dishonesty.
But if you don't lie,
you might fail the task
your Mother and the Emperor gave you.
Still,
I don't know how to lie.
Don't worry.
It's simple.
I will teach you.
[Qi]
What has happened?
What is going on?
Congratulations, everyone.
You have finally escaped
the grave danger.
Grave danger?
While the diplomatic corps left Qi
and entered the land of the Qing State,
someone had been following us
and spying on us.
Your Highness,
you are exaggerating the danger.
Ever since the diplomatic corps
entered the Qing State,
we have been under military protection.
No one dares to attack us.
Still, there is someone,
even a legion, who can't stop.
Could it be the Grandmaster?
Exactly.
Grandmaster?
Grandmaster
is more powerful than an army.
In this case, why did
the Grandmaster attack us?
Before Mr. Zhuang Mohan's pass,
he entrusted Mr. Fan Xian
with his important collection.
What does that symbolize?
It symbolizes the literary succession.
Precisely.
Literary talents only emerge
between our two states.
What would others think?
That's right.
It must be the foreign barbarian clan.
It's Dongyi City.
Your Highness, how did you know
about Grandmaster?
I saw
someone from the diplomatic corps
confront the Grandmaster alone.
He risked his own life
to secure the literary succession
and protect your lives.
- Who?
- Who is this person?
I don't know.
It must be an expert.
It must be.
He is brave enough to confront
the Grandmaster alone.
That's Fan Xian.
Don't come closer.
Mr. Fan.
Fan Xian?
Aren't you already dead?
Mr. Fan,
what is going on?
Please tell us.
Right.
Forget it.
It really doesn't matter.
Mr. Fan doesn't want to take credit.
But all of you
have the right to know the truth.
Qinian, no.
Mr. Fan!
Gentlemen,
when confronting the Grandmaster,
Mr. Fan couldn't do anything
but fake his death.
Only if Mr. Fan died
would the literary succession
be interrupted
and the Grandmaster
wouldn't attack the diplomatic corps.
That's how he protected all of you.
Turns out Mr. Fan faked his death
to protect our lives.
He is doing this for the Qing State.
It's all thanks to him.
It's not worth mentioning.
Right.
Your Highness.
You ran into this incident
by accident.
Thank you
for keeping this secret for me.
Literature greatly concerns
the state itself.
Qi and Southern Qing
should share it.
No one else should
get their hands on it.
- That's right.
- Please be seated, Your Highness.
Here's water.
Mr. Fan,
which Grandmaster you encountered?
We didn't fight.
If the Grandmaster had fought me,
I would have been dead by now.
I only saw from a distance
that the person was using a sword.
Your question seems rather unnecessary.
Who else could it be among the four Grandmasters
except Northern Qi and Qing?
It's Sigu Jian.
I didn't really get a good look.
I don't want to blame the wrong person.
We can't make an accusation
without proof.
What if he comes to seek revenge
for this?
Right.
Thank you, Mr. Fan.
For the Qing State all the way.
The Qing State!
Silence.
You have an hour
to get ready and break camp.
After that,
we will depart without delay.
Knowing that Mr. Fan is in one piece
is a blessing to the Qing State.
Deliver this message back
to the Capital immediately.
Yes.
Yes, Mr. Yan.
Let's go.
Deliver this message back
to the Capital immediately.
Yes.
Mr. Fan is truly a blessing
to the Qing State.
Exactly.
Finally, I came back to life.
Yes, you did.
Mr. Fan,
aren't you afraid
that Sigu Jian will come after you?
If he had to come
for a trivial matter like this,
he would have come already.
Thank you for cooperating with us,
Your Highness.
Mr. Fan,
may I ask you
something?
Ask away.
The two states have a marriage alliance.
Do you know
what the First Prince is like?
The First Prince has been stationed
outside for years.
I have never met him before.
Have you met the First Prince before?
No.
Watch your step.
Mr. Yan.
Thank you.
You died
by my hand,
yet came back to life by my mouth.
Fan Xian,
it won't happen again.
Wang,
there is a man ahead.
Is he here to receive
the diplomatic corps?
How come he is alone?
His face seems familiar.
Mr. Fan!
You are finally back.
Mr. Fan.
Official Xin, do you want
to rest in the carriage?
Official Xin, here you go.
Slowly.
Thanks.
Mr...
Mr. Fan,
you have made contributions
to the state on this trip.
[Xin Qiwu, Vice Minister of the Court of State Ceremonial]
You will probably be promoted.
Congratulations.
By the looks of it,
His Majesty didn't blame me
for deceiving him.
His Majesty didn't say about it.
He asks us to receive
the diplomatic corps.
Thank you, Official Xin.
Should we enter the Capital now?
Um.
The arrival of the diplomatic corps
is on everyone's radar.
Well.
The Ministry of Rites has already
prepared a ceremony.
It's just...
What is it? Tell us.
It's coincidental
that the First Prince
returns from the army
today.
What a coincidence.
Supposedly, you could've avoided each other.
Unfortunately,
the official road in the east
was washed away the other day
due to the rising water,
and the First Prince suddenly
changed his schedule.
So, both of you will be using
the north gate.
Where is he now?
He is not far away.
Less than three li from here.
So?
The cavalry guards of the First Prince
will arrive soon.
So, it is not good if both convoys
crowd outside the city?
Exactly.
The Ministry of Rites sends you over
to persuade me to make way.
After all, he is the prince.
Mr. Fan, you have worked hard.
So, you may
take a rest
by the roadside.
Once the First Prince enters the city,
officers of the Ministry of Rites
and the Court of State Ceremonial
will come out of the city
to welcome the diplomatic corps.
You could've sent over
a runner
to inform.
Why did you come here personally?
It's fine.
I have missed you so much.
Look,
I was so excited
that I couldn't sleep last night.
Look at how excited I am
after seeing you.
Tears are bursting out.
Official Xin, stop.
You can cry later.
All right.
I will cry later.
Could you please make way...
This is simple.
Yes.
I can't decide.
Do you know the Crown Princess
of Northern Qi is in the convoy?
I do.
Do you also know
she'll be the First Princess Consort
after the marriage alliance is formed?
I do.
So, should we ask for her permission
to make way?
I don't think this is necessary.
You don't want to let her know?
That's a good idea.
Good. Everyone heard that?
Yes.
It's Official Xin's idea
to keep this from the future
First Princess Consort.
Don't.
Well...
We should ask for her permission.
Sure.
Anything you say, Official Xin.
No.
No, I didn't mean that.
Official Xin.
Please, don't.
I can't decide on this.
What a weird coincidence.
It's said that he changed his schedule.
He changed his schedule,
and it clashes with mine?
It's said that the princess's carriage
represents the state's dignity.
But I think
both of you are going to be a family.
So, there is no need to argue over this.
Not a problem.
♪ The youth raises his head ♪
♪ As he moves toward his moon ♪
♪ People tease him for being delusional ♪
♪ Wondering why he is so unconventional ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ How could it remain unstained? ♪
♪ If silver tael has a value ♪
♪ Who can truly be carefree? ♪
♪ All of you are right ♪
♪ He said: "Please" ♪
♪ "Make way" ♪
♪ "Let me drink until I drop" ♪
♪ On the court ♪
♪ I recite several verses ♪
♪ Let me wear a white robe ♪
♪ And cross the alley
filled with insanity ♪
♪ To scoop up the moon's reflection
in the muddy pond ♪
♪ Sirs, please forgive me ♪
♪ Your words of advice ♪
♪ I understand,
but I don't want to pretend ♪
♪ People search for the golden land ♪
♪ While I search for the moon ♪
♪ Why should we travel together? ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Thank you ♪
♪ Excuse me ♪
♪ You are you ♪
♪ I am me ♪
♪ Wearing a white robe
when crossing a muddy pond ♪
♪ Remarkably worldly-wise
yet hopelessly romantic ♪
♪ Know what you love ♪
♪ Don't change ♪
♪ If one has witnessed
both light and shadow ♪
♪ Yet retains their innocence ♪
♪ They shall be cloaked in moonlight ♪
♪ As they journey through the night ♪